Naruth Kongurai

Web (Front-End) & Mobile App Developer & Technical Writer/Blogger

1128 NE 41^{st.} Cedar E302-B, Seattle, WA 98105

+1 (206) 201-9256 | contact@naruthk.com | 🎓 www.naruthk.com | 🗓 naruthkongurai | 🕘 naruthk

Summary

Specializes in web (front-end) and mobile application development. Super nerd who loves using the command-line-interface to develop web and mobile projects. Interested in learning new technologies and devising a better problem-solving method for challenging and serious tasks. Competitive in nature. Loves contributing to open-source projects and writing technical posts as a technical writer.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, Swift, Javascript, PHP Operating Systems: Windows, Mac OS Libraries & Tools: React, SCSS, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Git Software: Photoshop, Android Studio, Xcode, Eclipse, VS Code

Work Experience

Ogilvy One Worldwide Bangkok, Thailand FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER INTERN 07/2017 - 09/2017

- Reduced webpage sizes and increased page load speed for Thailand's NIVEA, SHOW DC Shopping Mall, and Milo websites
- Discussed UX/UI design changes with clients and Product Lead, and turned Photoshop templates to full-scale websites
- Developed API (PHP and Javascript) for fetching more than 1000+ NIVEA's customers survey reports
- Redesigned and implemented HTML email templates (Foundation-based) for Samsung Asia

Bitsee (Start-up Company)

Seattle, WA USA

ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER INTERN

01/2017 - 03/2017

- Solely designed and built a Tutorial Section, including an interactive tutorial walkthrough that makes the app easier to navigate
- Created the company's official website (HTML5 Boilerplate, Bootstrap and jQuery), featuring an interactive app showcase design
- Conducted unit testing on Android Studio and managed the pre-release test (beta) involving more than 100+ volunteered users

CP All Plc. Bangkok, Thailand 07/2016 - 09/2016

ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER INTERN

- Solely built a rating application deployed and used internally by 7-Eleven convenience stores (9000+ stores) in 2 months.
- Created a back-end server using PHP and MySQL to store incoming data (survey results) uploaded by the mobile application
- Built a front-end website to retrieve the rating results and display them to registered users

Projects

Mobile - "Daily Notes - Distraction-Free"

Apple App Store | 10/2017

Developed a distraction-free note-taking app (plain text format); available on the App Store for the iPhone and iPad.

Website - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineer (IEEE) Club

students.washington.edu/hknieee | 10/2017

• Customized an existing Wordpress theme to fit the organization's desired design.

CLI - Python Command-Line-Interface App for Fetching Soccer Scores

github.com/naruthk | 08/2017

Connected with external APIs to perform the functions of retrieving fixtures, table standings, and players' information

Education

University of Washington - Bachelor of Arts in Communication | Informatics (Minor) Seattle, WA | 09/2014 - Expected: 06/2018